A Guide to the Board Minutes and Record Books of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, 1934-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Board Minutes and Record Books of the Virginia Dept. of Alcoholic Beverage Control Board 1934-1998
The Library of Virginia
44438
157 volumes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred 14 Aug 2009
Biographical Information
The Virginia Alcoholic Beverage Control Board and its administrative arm, the Virginia Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, were created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 7, 1934. The act, known as the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, which the department was established to administer, specified the circumstances under which alcoholic beverages could be purchased and consumed. The act has been amended over the years. A major change occurred on February 7, 1968, when the General Assembly approved the sale of mixed drinks on a local option basis. The Board has three members appointed by the governor and confirmed by the General Assembly. It establishes rules and policies governing the Department, which controls through licenses and permits, the manufacture, bottling, selling, advertising, and transporting of alcoholic beverages; operates state stores for the sale of beverages, other than beer, to consumers and licensees. The Commissioner operates out of the Richmond office, with district offices established in Abingdon, Alexandria, Charlottesville, Chesapeake, Hampton, Lynchburg, Roanoke, and Staunton.
Scope and Content
Contains minute books of the Board of Alcoholic Beverage Control from 1934 until 1998. Also contains record books containing orders, including administrative and regulatory orders, from 1934 until 1985.
Arrangement
Arranged by type of record and then chronologically or alphabetically as appropriate.
Contents List
- Record Book 1 1934 Mar 22 - 1935 June 29
- Record Book 2 1935 July 1 - 1937 Apr 30
- Record Book 3 1937 May 4 - 1938 Nov 30
- Record Book 4 1938 Dec 1 - 1940 June 30
- Record Book 5 1940 July 1 - 1942 June 30
- Record Book 6 1942 July 1 - 1944 June 30
- Record Book 7 1944 July 1 - 1946 June 30
- Record Book 8 1946 July 1 - 1948 June 30
- Record Book 9 1948 July 1 - 1950 June 30
- Record Book 10 1950 July 1 - 1952 June 30
- Record Book 11 1952 July 1 - 1985 June 6
- Record Book Index, Index to Volumes 1-8 1934 Mar 22 - 1948 June 30
- Record Book Index 2, Index to Volumes 9-11 1948 July 1 - 1985 June 6
- Minute Book 1 1934 Mar 22 - 1934 Aug 31
- Minute Book 2 1934 Sept 6 - 1934 Dec 31
- Minute Book 3 1935 Jan 3 - 1935 June 29
- Minute Book 4 1935 July 9 - 1935 Dec 30
- Minute Book 5 1936 Jan 22 - 1936 June 30
- Minute Book 6 1936 July 2 - 1936 Nov 30
- Minute Book 7 1936 Dec 1 - 1937 Apr 30
- Minute Book 8 1937 May 4 - 1937 Aug 30
- Minute Book 9 1937 Sept 1 - 1937 Dec 30
- Minute Book 10 1938 Jan 3 - 1938 June 30
- Minute Book 11 1938 July 1 - 1938 Oct 31
- MInute Book 12 1938 Nov 3 - 1939 Mar 30
- Minute Book 13 1939 Apr 3 - 1939 June 30
- Minute Book 14 1939 July 1 - 1939 Sept 29
- Minute Book 15 1939 Oct 3 - 1940 Mar 26
- Minute Book 16 1940 Apr 2 - 1940 June 28
- Minute Book 17 1940 July 1 - 1940 Dec 27
- Minute Book 18 1941 Jan 3 - 1941 June 26
- Minute Book 19 1941 July 1 - 1941 Oct 30
- Minute Book 20 1941 Nov 5 - 1942 Apr 30
- Minute Book 21 1942 May 1 - 1942 Jun 29
- Minute Book 22 1942 Oct 1 - 1943 Mar 31
- Minute Book 23 1943 Apr 1 - 1943 Sept 30
- Minute Book 24 1943 Oct 1 - 1944 Apr 28
- Minute Book 25 1944 May 1 - 1944 Oct 31
- Minute Book 26 1944 Nov 1 - 1945 Apr 30
- Minute Book 27 1945 May 1 - 1945 Oct 31
- Minute Book 28 1945 Nov 1 - 1946 Apr 30
- Minute Book 29 1946 May 1 - 1946 Oct 31
- Minute Book 30 1946 Nov 6 - 1947 May 29
- Minute Book 31 1947 June 2 - 1947 Dec 31
- Minute Book 32 1948 Jan 6 - 1948 July 30
- Minute Book 33 1948 Aug 2 - 1948 Dec 30
- Minute Book 34 1949 Jan 4 - 1949 July 28
- Minute Book 35 1949 Aug 1 - 1950 Jan 31
- Minute Book 36 1950 Feb 1 - 1950 July 31
- Minute Book 37 1950 Aug 1 - 1951 Jan 30
- Minute Book 38 1951 Feb 1 - 1951 July 31
- Minute Book 39 1951 Aug 2 - 1952 Mar 31
- Minute Book 40 1952 Apr 1 - 1952 Dec 31
- Minute Book 41 1953 Jan 2 - 1953 June 30
- Minute Book 42 1953 Oct 1 - 1954 June 30
- Minute Book 43 1954 July 1 - 1955 Jan 27
- Minute Book 44 1955 Feb 1 - 1955 Sept 26
- Minute Book 45 1955 Oct 3 - 1956 June 26
- Minute Book 46 1956 July 2 - 1957 Mar 29
- Minute Book 47 1957 Apr 3 - 1957 Dec 31
- Minute Book 48 1958 Jan 2 - 1958 Sept 30
- Minute Book 49 1958 Oct 2 - 1959 Aug 5
- Minute Book 50 1959 Aug 5 - 1960 Apr 22
- Minute Book 51 1960 May 10 - 1960 Dec 29
- Minute Book 52 1961 Jan 3 - 1961 June 29
- Minute Book 53 1961 Oct 3 - 1962 June 29
- Minute Book 54 1962 July 3 - 1963 Mar 29
- Minute Book 55 1963 Apr 4 - 1963 Dec 30
- Minute Book 65 1964 Jan 2 - 1964 Sept 30
- Minute Book 57 1964 Oct 2 - 1965 Sept 30
- Minute Book 58 1965 Oct 5 - 1966 Aug 30
- Minute Book 59 1966 Sept 6 - 1967 Aug 31
- Minute Book 60 1967 Sept 1 - 1968 Sept 30
- Minute Book 61 1968 Oct 1 - 1969 Sept 30
- Minute Book 62 1969 Oct 1 - 1970 Oct 30
- Minute Book 63 1970 Nov 3 - 1971 June 30
- Minute Book 64 1971 July 1 - 1972 June 6
- Minute Book 65 1972 June 9 - 1973 Mar 30
- Minute Book 66 1973 Apr 3 - 1974 Mar 29
- Minute Book 67 1974 Apr 2 - 1975 Jan 27
- Minute Book 68 1975 Feb 3 - 1975 Dec 23
- Minute Book 69 1976 Jan 2 - 1976 Dec 19
- Minute Book 70 1977 Jan 3 - 1977 Dec 21
- Minute Book 71 1978 Jan 5 - 1978 Sept 27
- Minute Book 72 1978 Oct 2 - 1979 Sept 26
- Minute Book 73 1979 Oct 1 - 1980 June 30
- Minute Book 74 1980 July 1 - 1981 Mar 31
- Minute Book 75 1981 Apr 6 - 1981 Dec 31
- Minute Book 76 1982 Jan 4 - 1982 Dec 29
- Minute Book 77 1983 Jan 3 - 1983 Dec 29
- Minute Book 78 1984 Jan 4 - 1984 Dec 28
- Minute Book 79 1985 Jan 2 - 1985 Dec 30
- Minute Book 80 1986 Jan 2 - 1986 Dec 23
- Minute Book 81 1987 Jan 9 - 1987 Dec 28
- Minute Book 82 1988 Jan 4 - 1988 Aug 4
- Minute Book 83 1988 Aug 12 - 1989 June 30
- Minute Book 84 1989 July 5 - 1990 Mar 31
- Minute Book 85 1990 Apr 2 - 1991 Mar 31
- Minute Book 86 1991 Apr 1 - 1992 Apr 30
- Minute Book 87 1992 May 1 - 1993 June 24
- Minute Book 88 1993 July 2 - 1994 Mar 31
- Minute Book 89 1994 Apr 1 - 1994 Dec 29
- Minute Book 90 1995 Jan 1 - 1995 Sept 26
- Minute Book 91 1995 Oct 2 - 1996 June 28
- Minute Book 92 1996 July 1 - 1998 June 25
- Minute Book 93 1997 July 1 - 1998 Mar 30
- Minute Book 94 1998 Apr 1 - 1998 Dec 28
- Index to Minutes, A 1934 Mar 22 - 1947 May 29
- Index to Minutes, A-2 1947 June 2 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, A-3 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, B 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, B-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, C 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, C-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, D 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, D-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, E 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, E-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, F 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, F-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, G 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, G-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, H 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, H-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, I 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, I-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, J 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, J-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, K 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, K-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, L 1934 Mar 22 - 1947 May 29
- Index to Minutes, L-2 1947 June 2 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, L-3 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, M 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, M-2
- Index to Minutes, N 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, N-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, O 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, O-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, P 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, P-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, Q 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Indext to Minutes, Q-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, R 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, R-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, S 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, S-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, T 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, T-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, U 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, U-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, V 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, V-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, W 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, W-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30
- Index to Minutes, X, Y, Z 1934 Mar 22 - 1960 Apr 22
- Index to Minutes, X, Y, Z-2 1960 May 10 - 1980 June 30